Gregory D'Souza

Patroclosstraat 32/2 • 1076NH Amsterdam

Phone: +31 (0) 622 581 501 ● E-Mail: gregdsouza@me.com

Date of Birth: 11th April 1986

Objective

Utilizing my diverse professional experiences, I want to enable an organization to amplify their impact. I want to contribute, learn and grow within an organization, through design and thoughtful brand building. With my varied experiences, I am able to adapt quickly and tackle problems with the most effective approach. I derive satisfaction from solving big problems. I would like to garner my strengths and entrepreneurial zeal to constantly add value to the organization and develop both professionally and personally. My creative thinking enables me to feel comfortable in a fast paced environment. I have varied interests, which inspires me and enables me to apply unique concepts unseen before.

Experience

Manager at Van Souza Ventures and DateKnight, The Netherlands

Aug 2014 - Present

- Designed and build an iPhone app DateKnight to help people plan exquisite dates in Amsterdam (pre-launch)
- Working with innovative alcohol brands to launch their product in the EU market, as an agent and consultant.
- Building brands and other experiences to help facilitate unique and shareable experiences.

Founder and Builder at Fastr, The Netherlands

Aug 2013 - Jul 2014

- Conceptualized and designed an iPhone app which was like a WhatsApp for Customer Service
- Developed deep insight into Customer Service as a business function and innovated in the space
- Enabled a shift from synchronous to asynchronous customer support and drove organizations towards that shift

S&OP Business Analyst at **Nike European HQ**, The Netherlands

Nov 2011 - July 2013

- Conceptualized and created a multi-KPI Dashboard to track business and operational targets
- Developed a globally aligned innovative process at enabling decision making through deep data analysis
- Implemented new S&OP process in America & Emerging Markets functions
- Introduced and implemented a new BI Solution BOARD to develop deep analysis to get to our root causes
- Assisted in the transformation of business focus from Product focus to Category execution

Strategy and Business Dev. Project Lead at Nike, Inc. (Logistics), Belgium

Dec 2009 - Oct 2011

- Developed a \$320 million Logistics Strategy Roadmap and plan with savings of \$1 billion over 10 years
- Streamlined internal data to provide an objective analysis of Long-term Business Growth
- Created a Supply Chain Network Model to visualize Complexity and Service Lead Time
- Suggested Capacity and capability additions to support Nike EMEA Business Growth
- Communicated research and analysis to Logistics Management, Europe and WHQ

Business Development Manager at Frantech Services, India

Sep 2008 - Nov 2009

- Managed internal relationships with Intl. Stakeholders connecting them to Indian Business
- Delivered sales of €55.000 by adding 2 customers within the Wire & Cable Industry

- Market Research Analysis of Wire & Cable and targeted expansion to Construction systems
- Initiated a partnership with Faresin, Italy to launched their Construction formwork systems in India

Education

Bachelor of Technology – Industrial Engineering at VJTI, Mumbai University

2004 - 2008

- Major in Supply Chain Management and Entrepreneurship
- Seminar on 'The Wal-mart' Supply Chain illustrating their innovative practices with efficiency and responsiveness

E-Commerce Professional at APTECH Computer Education

2001

Comprehensive and broad technical and business coverage of the domain of running an Online Webshop

Extra-Curricular Activities

Marketing and Fundraising at The Music Therapy Trust, India

Feb 2008 - May 2008

- Initiated the Set-up of the UK-based organization in India for 'Music therapy for Autism'
- Generated funds (€18.000) for operational expenses and creation of 1st Indian Diploma in Music Therapy
- Created awareness through the media (print, TV) to showcase the Non-governmental organization.

Vice President – External Relations at AIESEC Mumbai, India

Jan 2006 - Dec 2007

- Within the Management team, developed plans for growth, operational functioning and strategic planning
- Revenue Generated (€5.000) through Product & Service Delivery and Event Organization (Empower, Dinner)
- Facilitated 3 Local Conferences and managed 3 Teams Events, Branding and Non Corporate Funding

Founding Student Member at The Indus Entrepreneurs, Mumbai

May 2007 - Apr 2008

- Youngest Member of a network of Entrepreneurs to discuss, mentor, incubate and deliver value to Startups and SME
- Participated at TiE Connect 2007 in Mumbai to network, tap into emerging trends and build connections.

Skills

Non-Technical

Presentation Skills, Creative, Flexible, Sales and Marketing,

Technical

MS OFFICE and BOARD BI Solutions Objective C, C++, JAVA, JavaScript, VB Script Web Design, COGNOS, Hyperion-Brio, BOARD

Languages

English, Hindi, (basic)

Interests

Keen Investor in Indian & Chinese Equity Markets – Supporter of Sustainable Development – International Business and Startups and Emerging Tech – Trend watcher of Product Design and Evolution – Global Market Dynamics – Sport